Finding Aid for Medical School (University of Michigan) Publications 1849-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sub-Unit Publications
  - Office of the Dean
    - Medical Service Plan
      - Policy Statements
        - Medical Service Plan, 1974 (Box 4)
        - Statement of Policies and Procedures for Management of Professional Fee Income, 1974 (Box 4)
      - Proceedings 1977 (Box 4)
      - Proposals
        - Associates in Psychiatry Medical Service Plan, 1979 (Box 4)
        - Medical Sculpture--A Unit Within Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery: Medical Service Plan, 1978 (Box 4)
        - Medical Service Plan: Salary and Income Proposals, 1975 (Box 4)
        - Neurology Associates Medical Service Plan, February, 1978 (Box 4)
        - Neurology Associates Medical Service Plan, September, 1978 (Box 4)
        - Obstetrics and Gynecology Associates Medical Service Plan, 1979 (Box 4)
        - Ophthalmology Associates Medical Service Plan, 1979 (Box 4)
        - Thoracic Surgery Associates Medical Service Plan, 1978 (Box 4)
        - Urologic Surgery Associates Medical Service Plan, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Physical Therapy
    - Brochures 1971 (Box 4)
  - Task Force on Medical Education
    - Task Force Report, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Task Force on Recruitment, Retention, and Career Development of the Medical School Faculty
    - Faculty Recruitment, Retention, and Career Development, 1992 (Box 4)
  - The Teaching Institute
    - Proceedings 1958 (Box 4)
  - The Victor C. Vaughan Society
    - Calendars 1995 (Box 4)
- Topical Publications
  The Topical Publications series contains programs and invitations from Medical School Alumni Reunions, commencement activities, conferences and symposia, and opening exercises.
  - Alumni Reunions
    - Directories
      - All Class Reunion 1938 (Box 4)
      - Multiple Class Reunions
        - Reunion Book for the classes of 1936, 1941, 1946, 1951, 1956, 1961, 1966, 1971, 1976, 1981, 1986, 1991, 1996 (Box 4)
        - Reunion Book for the classes of 1932, 1937, 1947, 1952, 1957, 1962, 1967, 1972, 1977, 1982, 1987, 1992, 1997 (Box 4)
        - Reunion Book for the classes of 1938, 1943A & B, 1948, 1953, 1958, 1963, 1968, 1973, 1978, 1983, 1988, 1993, 1998 (Box 4)
        - Reunion Book for the classes of 1934, 1939, 1944, 1949, 1954, 1959, 1964, 1969, 1974, 1979, 1984, 1989, 1994, 1999 (Box 4)
      - Individual Class Reunions
        - Class of 1898
          - The Tricensium Quintum: Medical Class 1898, 1936 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1923
          - 50th Reunion Roster: Class of 1923, 1973 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1935
          - 1935 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1939
          - 55th Medical School Reunion, September 23-24, 1994 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1940
          - 1940 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1945
          - 1945 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1950
          - 1950 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1955
          - 1955 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1959
          - 35th Medical School Reunion, September 23-24, 1994 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1960
          - 1960 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1964
          - 30th Medical School Reunion, September 23-24, 1994 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1965
          - 1965 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1970
          - 1970 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1974
          - 20th Medical School Reunion, September 23-24, 1994 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1975
          - 1975 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1979
          - 15th Medical School Reunion, September 23-24, 1994 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1980
          - 1980 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1984
          - 10th Medical School Reunion, September 23-24, 1994 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1985
          - 1985 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
        - Class of 1990
          - 1990 Medical School Reunion, October 6-8, 1995, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Programs 1938-1956, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Commencement
    - Invitations 1991-1994 (Box 5)
    - Programs
      - Class Day Ceremony and Honors Convocation, 1964, 1982-1986 (Box 5)
      - Graduation Exercises, 1942-1946 (Box 5)
      - Graduation Festivities, 1987-1994, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Conferences/Symposia
    - Conference on Ethics, Humanism and Medicine, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Martin Luther King Day Commemorative Health Care Program
      - ...on Infant Mortality Among Minority Children, 1988 (Box 5)
      - ...on Hypertension in Blacks, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Medical Computing at the University of Michigan, undated (Box 5)
    - Medstart Conference
      - Building Coalitions for Children: Turning Words into Action, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Sexuality and Physical Disability: Michigan Training Seminar for Health and Helping Professions, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Symposium on Substance Abuse, 1986 (Box 5)
    - U of M Celebrates the Centennial of the National Institutes of Health, 1987 (Box 5)
    - U of M Student Medical Research Forum, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Opening Exercises
    - Programs 1942-1950 (Box 5)
- Student Publications
  The Student Publications series (.5 linear feet) contains newsletters from the Black Medical Association and the Phi Chi Medical Fraternity, as well as two student handbooks produced by the Medical Student Council, and an Alumni Directory (1969) from the Galens Honorary Medical Society. The bulk of this series is composed of the student newsletter, The Paeon, which ran regularly from 1968, then intermittently since the beginning of the 1980's.
  The Medical School yearbook Aequanimitas, is individually catalogued under the call number Fimu C41. The Bentley Historical Library holds a nearly complete run from 1957 through 1995.
  - The Black Medical Association (Box 5)
    - Newsletters
      - The Black Physician, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Programs circa 1993 (Box 5)
  - Galen's Medical Society
    - Directories
      - Alumni Directory, 1961, 1964, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Programs
      - Banquet 1947, 1964 (Box 5)
      - Galens Smoker 1985-1988 (Box 5)
  - General
    - Newsletters
      - The Paeon, 1968-1987, 9 folders (Box 5)
      - Thymico-Lymphatic Constitution, 1946 (Box 5)
  - Medical Student Council
    - Manuals
      - The Medical Students Guide to Life in Ann Arbor, 1974 (Box 5)
      - Student Handbook U of M Medical School, 1977/78 (Box 5)
  - Phi Chi Medical Fraternity
    - Newsletters
      - Phi Chi Quarterly, 1928 (Box 5)
- Archived Medical School Website (2011 Accession)
  The Archived Medical School Website documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the School. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the School. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Archived Medical School home page 2010-[ongoing]
  - Archived websites related to the Medical School 2010-[ongoing]